To get a single subject
dance credential
in California,
Most people start by earning
a college degree in dance.
This shows the state
that you have subject matter competency,
which I know you already do.
This is especially important
for the dance credential,
because the programs
in the state
teach you how to teach,
but not what to teach.
That part comes from you.
If you don't have
a degree in dance,
but you took at least 32 units
of coursework in college, that is dance related,
that will work too.
Once you have your bachelor's degree,
you will apply to
and enroll in a program
to get your single subject
credential in dance.
And there are now more than 13 programs
all over the state from Sacramento to San Diego,
where you can do just that.
Some are totally remote
or online,
some are fully in-person,
and some have hybrid options.
Take a look at the programs
and decide
which one makes the most sense for you.
Once you're in a single subject credential program,
we'd also recommend getting a PE credential as well.
That way, you'll be able to offer a dance class
and your students can receive
either dance or PE credits for the course.
This makes you super marketable for schools,
and learning
more is always a good thing.